video on this so you know just don't
become a tech bigot this is coming from
a guy who has been a tech bigot
before um I don't know what it is but
there's something about being young that
makes you an and and you know
ambitious um that tends to make you into
more of a tech bigot uh what is a bigot
bigot is a person with you know extreme
biases who think everybody else is a
if you don't agree with you and
the again this is a part this video is a
part of a series about mentally
preparing for a tech job and the warning
is it's very cautionary I don't really
need to do a lot about this um I do have
a couple stories about it though so you
can stick around for the stories but the
the takeaway is don't allow yourself to
think that just because you like a
particular
technology um that it is the only
solution it might not even be the best
solution and picking the best technology
for
um a specific problem may not have
anything to do with how good the
technology is it may have to do more
with the team that's
maintaining uh the solution long term so
let me give you a very specific example
I've talked about this story before but
I once helped a good friend of
mine uh create a WordPress site uh in
PHP which if anybody knows me you know
what I think about that and for her um
her uh what's the word the you know the
homeowners association right and this is
a part of a bigger video about about
anticipating the needs about why you
should not be a web Deb and a bunch of
reasons like that but it came about
because this person wanted to pay me and
I said you know who's going to maintain
it and she was like it's going to be me
so and I again I talk about this in
another video but why it's important
that you choose solutions that are best
for the problem at hand and this
particular problem was very specific to
this woman who wanted to maintain the
site for herself now I hate PHP PHP has
destroyed projects that I have run
before because of memory leaks I know
PHP in 2024 is way better than it was in
2004 when I started you know writing
Damons in it which is completely stupid
um the point is that you know because I
was not you know anti- WordPress which
in so many ways another person I helped
by the way who did a yoga site they were
hacked by a plug-in and they lost their
entire yoga site um um because PHP and
so you know you would think that that
would make me say thou shalt not you
know recommend to any further people how
to use PHP PHP sucks um but when you
consider the solution if if you're truly
in the right mindset that's going to get
you the trust that you need to get good
and to get employed and to get advanced
in your career your employer the person
is going to be paying you your your
customers whether your customers or your
employer they care that to know that you
are going to be thinking about their
needs all of their needs not just
because you think Arch is the coolest
Linux on the planet therefore you're
going to do everything in Arch and
you're going to run Arch on your laptop
blah blah blah and you're going to
install Arch on the server platforms God
help you if you do that by the
way dude if you were to install Arch and
some Enterprise technology camps you
would literally lose your job over that
um there's other jobs there's other
companies such as Val where if you used
Arch it would be part of your job point
is you're not biased you're not a bigot
you can have preferences you can have
opinions God knows I do but that does
not mean that they color every
recommendation you make for a solution
for the person that you are being paid
to help
or the person that you just care about
who's asking you a question which
language should I learn you don't just
blurt out go or rust you ask them
socratically what what do you want to
do that that is that is what it means to
not be attch bigot it means to think
about the needs of the person asking the
question whether that be somebody who's
paying you or otherwise what is it that
they need and and maybe maybe if they're
you know
uh maybe if there somebody in the
science field who wants to you know
write an ex you know a real a really
quickly handled thing maybe python is
the best language for them maybe maybe
emac is the best editor for them because
they're never ever leaving their
terminal may you know what I'm saying
there there are a lot there are a lot of
considerations um that said and I'll
conclude the video with this I have been
roundly criticized for being a tech
bigot and particularly because I've been
so anti- rust uh there's actually an
entire Reddit Thread about my rust um
you know disagreements to be fair I went
into rust wanting to like it I really
did and at the time I was kind of
frustrated because it just didn't I
first of all I hated the syntax I didn't
do anything I wanted to I didn't like
the governance committee and there's a
million reasons I but but since then I
mean even then I wasn't a bigot I I was
like you know what I I don't feel like
the I don't feel like the hype matches
the reality and I said so and I got
cancelled by a bunch of people for
calling it out um and I I still don't
think that's being a tech bigot I and
that this goes into another video which
I'll do immediately called what it means
to have strong opinions and and when you
should know to change those opinions and
how that prevents you from being a tech
bigot and you're being able to change
your opinions for example um my position
on Rust um so stay tuned for another
video on that one